Michael Iodice

Littleton, CO 80127 | 617-835-0158 | miodice3@gmail.com <u>Github</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Blog</u>

Full Stack Software Engineer

Experienced in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript and React with a background in Real Estate Portfolio Management and Development. Strong skills in project management and experience in working in chaotic environments. Skilled in identifying the unspoken needs within individuals, projects and processes.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby / Ruby on Rails, basic SQL, ActiveRecord, JavaScript, React / Redux, Arduino/C++/IOT devices, GitHub

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Automobile Emissions Analyzer - github | UsefulTool.com | demo

A React / Redux application comparing emissions data for any vehicle in the US federal database.

- Utilizes multiple APIs and graph libraries to transform inaccessible API data to a consumable format and facilitate the transfer of knowledge via a simple chart
- Electric Vehicles calculate attributable emissions with Britain's Electric Utility API, showing real time emissions
- Generates state dynamically to allow future expandability to compare as many vehicles as user desires at a single time.

Sol-Search - github | sol-search.com | demo

An MVC full stack Rails application serving as a marketplace for renewable energy which significantly decreases the friction involved with pairing consumers and producers for renewable energy projects

- Implemented Google OAuth to verify user accounts and 'confirm email' feature for manual signups to reduce spam
- Production code hosted to Heroku to enable public use of website
- Structured Postgres users table as a self referential join with ActiveRecord, enabling users to enter contracts as producers or consumers with a single account allowing for a seamless experience
- Email notifications provide instant updates when contracts are modified to maintain deal momentum

Motivational Box github | demo

A scratch made web connected lockbox complete with task list application. Box unlocks itself upon task list completion from a smartphone, optimized for minimum power consumption

- Used a low cost wifi enabled microcontroller to host a web server that triggers different hardware actions depending on which route is requested from the companion application
- Addition of small screen allows users to configure the box to their phone application, and greets the user with a fun
 message as they complete their tasks and the lock opens
- Utilized MIT's App Inventor tool to create the task list application, added a database to provide persistence and allow tasks and status to repopulate after application is closed

EXPERIENCE

Chatham Development Co.

Newton, MA

Project Management, Portfolio Management

09/2013 - 03/2020

- Spearheaded sales of 7 large properties totalling \$85mm over a 3 year period on behalf of owners
- Entrusted to take lead role in coordinating legal defense of frivolous lawsuit subject of \$65mm of trust assets
- Counselled client on expense recovery strategies, resulting in full recovery of wages, legal fees and recovery of unpaid trustee fees resulting in an additional \$1mm for our client

Brown Brothers Harriman

Boston, MA 07/2010 - 08/2013

Senior Client Account Manager, ETF Service Group

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Full Time Online, Castle Rock, CO

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript

09/ 2020 - Current

Boston University
Bachelor of Arts in Economics

Boston, MA 05/ 2009